<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology adoption | Rachel X. Peng</title>
    <link>https://rxpeng.github.io/tag/technology-adoption/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://rxpeng.github.io/tag/technology-adoption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Technology adoption</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://rxpeng.github.io/media/icon_hudf86b74585956befc08dcd2dcd0519f3_52782_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Technology adoption</title>
      <link>https://rxpeng.github.io/tag/technology-adoption/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>In technology we trust?</title>
      <link>https://rxpeng.github.io/project/adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rxpeng.github.io/project/adoption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study sets out to investigate the factors that influence the adoption intention of e-health services among the digital natives college students in China. The primary focus is to examine the influence of trust on adoption intention in an e-health context, while including a three-way interaction of perceived benefit, perceived risk and offline healthcare habits. It utilizes a sample of students from two public universities in southwest China (N = 583). While confirming previous research findings that the trust positively affects the adoption intention and that perceived benefit and perceived risk are respectively positive and negative mediators in the trust-adoption intention relationship, our moderated mediation analysis improves on prior research by demonstrating how the mediation effect of perceived benefit might vary depending on the two moderators, perceived risk and offline healthcare habits. Only when respondents have a low level of habitual use of offline channels for medical treatment or health consultation, would the perceived risk negatively moderate the direct effect of trust on adoption intention. Meanwhile, the mediation effect of perceived benefit on the trust-adoption intention relationship through the indirect path is higher as perceived risk increases. The implications for health practitioners are also discussed based on our findings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
