<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anti-vaccination | Rachel X. Peng</title>
    <link>https://rxpeng.github.io/tag/anti-vaccination/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://rxpeng.github.io/tag/anti-vaccination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Anti-vaccination</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://rxpeng.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Anti-vaccination</title>
      <link>https://rxpeng.github.io/tag/anti-vaccination/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Infinity Vaccine War</title>
      <link>https://rxpeng.github.io/project/vaxxer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rxpeng.github.io/project/vaxxer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As public health professionals strive to promote vaccines for inoculation effort, fervent anti-vaccination movements are marshaling against it. This study is motived by a need to better understand the online discussion around vaccination. We identified the sentiments, emotions and topics of pro- and anti-vaxxers’ tweets, investigated their change since the pandemic started, also further examined the associations between these content features and audiences’ engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizing a snowball sampling method, data were collected from the Twitter accounts of 100 pro-vaxxers (266,672 tweets) and 100 anti-vaxxers (248,027 tweets). We are adopting a lexicon-based approach for sentiment analysis, and structural topic modeling to extract the topics. And we use hurdle negative binomial model to test the relationships among sentiment, emotion, topics and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sentiment analysis shows that the average sentiment of pro-vaxxers’ tweets is more positive, while of anti-vaxxers’ tweets is more negative. The cues of Trust encourage retweeting and the emotion of Anger encourages likes in general. Topic modeling of tweets yields the top15 topics for pro- and anti-vaxxers separately. Among the pro-vaxxers’ tweets, the topics of “Child protection” and “COVID-19 situation” are positively predicting audiences’ engagement. For anti-vaxxers, the topics of “Supporting Trump”, “Injured children”, “COVID-19 situation”, “Media propaganda”, and “Community building” are more appealing to audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study generates insights into the development of emotionally appealing content and effective vaccine promotion strategies while combating COVID-19 and moving toward a global recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
